ARCHITA MUKHERJEE

SUMMARY

Data analyst with 5+ years of experience interpreting and analyzing large volume of data in order to drive successful business solutions thus facilitating well informed decision making. I have used tools like SAS, Advanced Excel, and SQL to perform data analysis.

EXPERIENCE

Team Leader-Reporting and Analysis | Medfin India Private Limited-A Cognizant Company, Kolkata December, 2015 – October, 2020

- Worked on healthcare project with large volume of data
- Responsible for reporting and delivering end reports to clients on daily, monthly basis also special reports as per client request
- Mentoring and training team members on report preparation
- Quality check of reports
- Used advanced excel, Base SAS, Ms Access, basics of SQL to perform data analysis, cleaning and transformation of data

MIS Assistant/Analyst | Child in Need Institute, Kolkata | January, 2015-December, 2015

- Management of all types of database of ASHA State Training Center
- Regular analysis of pre and post training assessment of trainees, training evaluation
- Development of MIS related formats, database design
- Data analysis of training related data using Ms. Access, Advanced Excel,SQL

Executive Communications | American TESOL Institute, Kolkata August, 2014 – January, 2015

- Facilitated TESOL course for mainly India operations
- Detailed orientation of the course to prospective students ,in person or telephonic, mail

Research Associate | Market Quotient Business Solutions, Kolkata June, 2013-February, 2014

- Web based research, market research, secondary research
- Worked on projects from different industries like FMCG, Education
- Used sources like Bloomberg, Factiva etc.

CONTACT

Email: amukherjee602@gmail.com

Phone: +91 9903718406 /

8777681084 **Address:** Mumbai

SKILLS

- SAS-Base, Advanced ,Macros
- Business Analysis
- Advanced Excel
- Power Query
- SQL
- Ms. Access

EDUCATION

- * Masters in Economics | IGNOU New Delhi | 2010-2012 - 58.45%
- * B.Sc. Economics (Honours), Calcutta University, Kolkata | 2005 – 2008 - 45.87%
- * 12 Th, Carmel High School, Kolkata | Economics, Statistics, Mathematics | 2003-2005 - 61.5 %
- * 10 Th, Carmel High School, Kolkata | 2003 - 71.72 %

Certifications

Data Analytics
 Certification from IVY
 Professional School,
 Kolkata- 2012-2013